U.S. Chamber of Commerce Publications 5332
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
U.S. Chamber of Commerce Publications
1919-1967
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
U.S. Chamber of Commerce
5332
1 cubic feet
1 linear ft.
Records (documents).
Publications of the U.S. Chamber of Commerce
5603955
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, April 08, 2014
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, March 11, 2019
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Chamber of Commerce of the United States of America
5603955
- General information from the Chamber of Commerce, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Item 1: Investment for Jobs, Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Scope and Contents
    By The Economic Research Department of The Chamber of Commerce of the United States. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: Communists within the Labor Movement: A Handbook on the Facts and Counter-Measures, Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
    By The Committee on Socialism and Communism. Item is in English.
  - Item 3: 1965 Congressional Handbook, Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
    By Chamber of Commerce of the United States. Item is in English.
  - Item 4: 1965 Political and Election Information, Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Item 5: 71 Million More Americans by 1985, Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Item 6: National Chamber Information Services, Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Item 7: Publications Directory and Price List, Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Item 8: The United States Balance of Payments Position, Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Item 9: Criteria for Government Spending, Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Item 10: The Packaging-Labeling Controls Bill (S. 985), Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
- War and Postwar Economies, 1943-1967; Publication (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Item 1: Policies and Controls in a War-Burdened Economy, Publication (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Item 2: Economic Problems of the Post-War, Publication (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Item 3: Economic Lessons of Postwar Recessions, Publication (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Item 4: Economic Lessons of Postwar Recessions, Publication (Box 1, Folder 2)
    By Chamber of Commerce of the United States. Copy 2. Item is in English.
  - Item 5: Policies and Controls in a War-Burdened Economy, Publication (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Information for Businesses, 1955-1967; Publication (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Item 1: Small Business: Its Role and its Problems, Publication (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Item 2: Associations in the Next Decade, Publication (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Item 3: Corporate Options for Increasing Minority Participation in the Economy, Publication (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Item 4: Profits: Something for Everyone, Publication (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Item 5: Private Employee Benefits in Distribution, Publication (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Government, Business, and Labor, 1963-1967; Publication (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Item 1: Government vs. Business: The Competition that Nobody Wants, Publication (Box 1, Folder 4)
    By Walter F. Carey. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: Choice or Compulsion?, Publication (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Item 3: The Menace of Restrictive Work Practices, Publication (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Item 4: Free Markets and Free Men, Publication (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Pamphlets on Economics, 1967; Publication (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Item 1: Business and Economic Forecasting, Publication (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Item 2: The Economics of the Money Supply, Publication (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Item 3: Economic Change and Adjustment, Publication (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Item 4: The Goals of Economic Policy, Publication (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Item 5: Government Spending and Economic Stability, Publication (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Economics and the Economy, 1960-1967; Publication (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Item 1: Can We Depression-Proof Our Economy?, Publication (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Item 2: Can We Depression-Proof Our Economy?, Publication (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Item 3: The Promise of Economic Growth, Publication (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Item 4: The Promise of Economic Growth, Publication (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Item 5: The Promise of Economic Growth, Publication (Box 1, Folder 6)
    By Chamber of Commerce of the United States. Copy 3. Item is in English.
- Poverty and Community Programs, 1930-1965; Publication (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Item 1: What Policies What Action for Community Development and Renewal?, Publication (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Item 2: The Concept of Poverty, Publication (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Item 3: Emergency Employment, Publication (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Welfare and Other Social Programs, 1945-1954; Publication (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Item 1: Welfare Plans and Collective Bargaining, Publication (Box 1, Folder 8)
    By Chamber of Commerce of the United States. April 1, 1950. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: Welfare Plans and Collective Bargaining, Publication (Box 1, Folder 8)
    By Chamber of Commerce of the United States. April 1, 1950; Copy 2. Item is in English.
  - Item 3: New Chamber Policy on Social Security Program for the Aged, Publication (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Item 4: Health Insurance in America, Publication (Box 1, Folder 8)
    By Chamber of Commerce of the United States. January, 1945. Item is in English.
- Unemployment, 1933-1962; Publication (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Item 1: Social Legislation, Publication (Box 1, Folder 9)
    By Chamber of Commerce of the United States. March, 1935. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: Automation and Unemployment, Publication (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Item 3: Providing Reserves Against Unemployment, Publication (Box 1, Folder 9)
    By Chamber of Commerce of the United States. June 1934. Item is in English.
  - Item 4: Unemployment Reserve Legislation, Publication (Box 1, Folder 9)
    By Chamber of Commerce of the United States. April, 1933. Item is in English.
  - Item 5: Unemployment: Some Neglected Causes, Publication (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Item 6: Disemployment Forces and Reemployment Prospects, Publication (Box 1, Folder 9)
    By Chamber of Commerce of the United States. May 1959. Item is in English.
  - Item 7: Statement on Proposals to Amend Unemployment Compensation, Publication (Box 1, Folder 9)
    By E.S. Willis. April 14, 1959. Item is in English.
- Labor/Union Information, 1919-1955; Publication (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Item 1: Could Foreign Competition Take My Job?, Publication (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Item 2: Moratorium in Industrial Strife, Publication (Box 1, Folder 10)
    By Albert W. Hawkes. June 7, 1941. Item is in English.
  - Item 3: Adjustment of Labor Disputes in Defense Industries, Publication (Box 1, Folder 10)
    By Chamber of Commerce of the United States. January 24, 1941. Item is in English.
  - Item 4: Labor and the American Economy, Publication (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Item 5: Reuther's Profit-Sharing Demand, Publication (Box 1, Folder 10)
    By Chamber of Commerce of the United States. May 1958. Item is in English.
  - Item 6: Labor's Impact on Transportation, Publication (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Item 7: Referendum No. 27 on the Report of the Committee on Industrial Relations Regarding Principles of Industrial Relations, Publication (Box 1, Folder 10)
    By Chamber of Commerce of the United States. April 16, 1919. Item is in English.
  - Item 8: Employee Rights Under the Taft-Hartley Act, Publication (Box 1, Folder 10)
    By Chamber of Commerce of the United States. January 1955. Item is in English.
  - Item 9: Labor in Politics, Publication (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Item 10: Background for Decision on Voluntary Union Membership, Publication (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Communism/Communist Infiltration, 1946-1947; Publication (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Item 1: Communists Within the Labor Movement, Publication (Box 1, Folder 11)
    By Chamber of Commerce of the United States. Small Copy. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: Communists Within the Labor Movement, Publication (Box 1, Folder 11)
    By Chamber of Commerce of the United States. Large Copy. Item is in English.
  - Item 3: Commuist Infiltration in the United States, Publication (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Inflation and Wage Policies, 1952-1961; Publication (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Item 1: The Mechanics of Inflation: An Analysis of Cost and Demand Pressures on the Price Level, Publication (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Item 2: Inflation, Unions and Wage Policy, Publication (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Item 3: Productivity and Wage Settlements, Publication (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Item 4: Price Control and Inflation, Publication (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Item 5: Wage Supplements: The Nonwage Labor Costs of Doing Business, Publication (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Effect Business through Employee and Community Relations, 1950-1954; Publication (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Item 1: "Backgrounds Developments in the Field of Private Pensions", Publication (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Item 2: Effective Employee and Community relations, Publication (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Item 3: How to Tell Your Business Story in Employee Publications, Publication (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Item 4: Developing a Better Understanding of Business Through Effective Employee and Community Relations, Publication (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Investment for Jobs/Sustaining Employment, 1947-1959; Publication (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Item 1: A Program for Sustaining Employment, Publication (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Item 2: Investment for Jobs, Publication (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Item 3: Investment for Jobs, Publication (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Management Action to Promote Business Stability, 1961; Publication (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Item 1: Management Action to Promote Business Stability, Publication (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Item 2: Management Action to Promote Business Stability, Publication (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Item 3: Management Action to Promote Business Stability, Publication (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Guaranteed Wage, 1948-1954; Publication (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Item 1: Jobs? Or Jobless Pay?, Publication (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Item 2: The Economics of the Guaranteed Wage, Publication (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Item 3: The Economics of the Guaranteed Wage, Publication (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Item 4: The Economics of the Guaranteed Wage, Publication (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Management and Worker Relations, 1927-1964; Publication (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Item 1: Employee Representation or Works Councils, Publication (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Item 2: The Role of Management Toward Worker Security, Publication (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Item 3: Better Business Relations Through Plant Tours, Publication (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Item 4: Better Business Relations Through Employee Meetings, Publication (Box 1, Folder 17)